Sandhya Kinnera

+91 8919627863, Hyderabad, Telangana(INDIA) kinnerasandhya22@gmail.com
LinkedIn Profile

OBJECTIVE

Highly motivated and quick-learning Back end Developer with [1+ years] of experience in developing back end components for mobile and web applications and seeking a challenging role in a dynamic organization where I can utilize my technical skills and contribute to the growth of the company.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology, Computer Science and Engineering(CSE): 2014 - 2018

Institution: KITS For Women, JNTU, Kodada, Ts

SKILLS

Programming Languages Python

Web Technologies HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Frameworks Django Rest Framework

Database SQLIte3, MySQL, PostgreSQL

Testing and Debugging Unit Testing

Version Control Git

API Tool Postman

Languages Known English, Hindi, Telugu

CERTIFICATIONS

IBM PY010EN: Python 101 for Data Science (Aug 2023)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Associate Software Engineer May 2022 - Aug 2023 Headrun Technologies Bangalore, KA(IND)

- Worked as Python Django Developer in Headrun Technologies from May 2022 to Aug 2023.
- Over 1.4 years of experience in back end development of both Web, Mobile and Client Server applications.
- Extensive experience in designing and developing RESTful APIs using Django and Django Rest Framework.
- Experience in working with front-end technologies like HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, and ability to collaborateeffectively with front-end developers to integrate front-end components with back-end logic.
- Analyzed and unit tested back end specifications after implementation and prepared test report to ensure allrequirements are met.
- Built and maintained a robust data model using Django's ORM, which resulted in improved query executionand application responsiveness.
- Demonstrated commitment to continuous professional growth, actively acquiring new knowledge and skills.
- As a cultural team member, actively contributed to events, fostering teamwork, promoting positivity, andstrengthening team dynamics.

e-Learning Developer Dec 2020 – Apr 2022 Rank Guru Technologies Pvt Ltd Hyderabad, TS(IND)

- Developed educational e-books and worksheets in an effective interactive way.
- Worked for conceptualized games.
- Developed and maintained educational projects in the manner of responsive web applications.
- Created storyboards, user flows, process flows and sitemaps to communicate interaction and design ideas.
- Presented designs and key deliverable to peers and executive level stakeholders.

PROJECTS

Title: Fourkites (May2023 – Aug2023)

Role: Backend Developer

Project Description:

FourKites, a supply chain management company, has the ability to track truckload, LTL, Rail, Inter modal, Ocean and Air loads. In this project, the data is scraped from the carrier websites, stored in databases and managed through APIs.

Responsibilities:

- Worked on back end components like data schema and scripts, APIs and tools.
- Ensure that all test cases are covered during unit testing after implementation.
- Upskilling every day by learning about and working on new features and enhancements in fourkites.
- Published applications to the Google Play Store and managed updates and maintenance of theseapplications.
- Collaborated with designers, product managers, and other developers to deliver high-quality software solutions.

Title: CoachPro (Nav2022 - May2023)

Role: Backend Developer Project Description:

Coach Pro is a marketplace mobile application that provides a platform for personal coaches to connectwith individuals seeking to enhance their health, wellness, and fitness.

Responsibilities:

- Analyze and understand client requirements, plan and strategize backend implementation to meet businessobjectives within specified timeline.
- Plan and strategically implement the backend to achieve company goals within the allotted period afteranalyzing and comprehending customer needs.
- Implement robust backend functionalities using Python and Django, ensuring adherence to codingstandards and best practices, for seamless data storage, retrieval, and manipulation.
- Collaborated effectively with front-end developers to integrate front-end components with backend logic.
- Maintained all API documentations to help the front-end team while integration.

Play store Links:

Sportx, Sports Business

Title: Dent-O (Jun2022-Oct2022)

Role: Backend Developer

Project Description:

Dent-o provides a complete solution to dental needs which includes conducting free dental campaigns, guidance to your nearby clinics, electronic dental records at your fingertips, clinic management, and so on and soforth.

Responsibilities:

- Developed back end components as per the client requirements.
- Integrated third-party libraries and APIs into the application to enhance its functionality.
- worked on bugs and enhancements like file compression and delivering within deadlines.
- Worked on few features, such as a video calling service utilizing Twilio & File compression in Dento, andlearned about a variety of sophisticated topics.
- Troubleshooting and debugging issues in existing code bases to ensure the smooth performance of applications.

Play store Links, Website:

Patient App, Doctor App, Clinic App, Dent-O

ACHIEVEMENTS

Promising Fresher Award (Q32022- Present)